

LU HTOO

MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER

CONTACT INFO

+95 9799899364

uhtookyaw98@gmail.com

luhtookyaw.github.ic

linkedin.com/in/lu-htoo-kyaw-382347188/

No-29, Lower Mandalay St, Mingalar Taung Nyunt Tsp, Yangon Region

SKILLS

Machine Learning

Computer Vision I Time Series Analysis I Reinforcement Learning

Data Science

Inferencial Statistics | Bayesian Statistics

Frameworks

^PyTorch I TensorFlow I Sklearn I OpenCV I Gym

Programming Languages
Python I JavaScript I PHP I C++

Unix/Linux

Version Control

Git I Github Actions I DVC

Database

MySQL | Neo4j | MongoDB | SQLite

Frontend

React JS | Vue JS | Streamlit

Backend

Node JS I Django I Flask I FastAPI

PROFILE

I am a Machine Learning Engineer, mainly experienced in development especially associated with Computer Vision, Time Series Analysis and passionate about all sorts of Machine Learning subjects. Being able to prove enthusiasm to take on any task to support the project team and enhance the team progress. Offer strong coding skills, vast knowledge of development materials, and confidence to overcome strict deadlines.

EXPERIENCE

WORLD BANK

Hybrid, Sep 2022 - Present

VILLAGE LINK (MYANMA AWBA)

Hybrid, Aug 2022 - Dec 2022

OMDENA

Remote, Apr 2022 - Present

MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER, CONTRACT

Main goal of this project is to extract land-cover classification mapping covering the whole region of Myanmar with Machine Learning using satellite imageries.

MACHINE LEARNING RESEARCHER, INTERNSHIP

My tasks and duties were to perform various GIS operations and remote sensing data analysis for obtaining multi-temporal geospatial datasets and to research deep learning models for classifying crop areas.

LITHA: MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER, CONTRACT

My task for this project was to deploy already trained natural learning processing model with fastapi backend, react frontend and neo4j database. Then, docker-compose was done to be readily deployable to AWS EC2.

DR-CADX: MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER, VOLUNTEER

The mission of the project was using AI to detect cervical cancer for women with inability to afford pathological tests in Africa, accompanied by 50 collaborators around the globe. We researched wide range of available datasets of microscope cytological image slides to build classification model corresponding with examining cells. We experimented some backbone architectures such as ResNet, RegNet, InceptionNet and VGGNet to extract feature representations so that they can be used in our custom-built neural architectures. I engaged a great deal of architectural researching and model implementation.

BONDY: MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER, VOLUNTEER

Main objective was using AI to monitor trees during reforestation process in Andramasina district, Madasgascar along with 30 collaborators from over 20 countries. During modelling process, we used CVAT tool for manual labeling and unsupervised methods for automatic labeling to drone images which were then used in experimenting models such as UNet, UNet++ and DeepLabv3 to segment trees in the area. Inferenced drone images were later combined with OpenDroneMap software to achieve field level estimation of the area. We used Google Earth Engine to obtain Sentinal-2 images and extract NDVI time series for charting purpose. Finally, a dashboard was build with Streamlit to provide our client insights. My participation was mainly in model building

Development Operations

Docker | Kubernetes | GCP

LANGUAGES

English

Speaking I Listening I Reading I Writing

REFERENCES

Available upon request.

but I also contributed significantly in data collection and pipeline orchestration.

SPARK FOUNDATION

Remote, May 2022 - Jun 2022

COMPUTER VISION & IOT, INTERNSHIP

I built two models in this program. The first one is social distancing detection. I firstly obtained urban drone image dataset from Kaggle and annotated people with CVAT, then I used prepared dataset to train YOLOv5. Final result was the calculation of distance between each person corresponding with drone elevation. The second model is face mask detection which I also used dataset from Kaggle but I trained SSD model from TFOD.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Feb 2019 - Feb 2022

UNIVERSITY OF YANGON

Dec 2014 - Dec 2019

SEAMEO CHAT REGIONAL CENTER FOR HISTORY AND TRADITION

Dec 2017 - Feb 2019

DIPLOMA IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

My passion lead me to the computer science and its famous sub-branch, Artificial Intelligence.

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN GEOLOGY

I learned all the basics of earth sciences throughout semesters of four.

DIPLOMA IN ENGLISH LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY

I have taken numerous courses on six levels of english language proficiency.

CERTIFICATIONS

COURSERA

Specializations, July 2020 Present

MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEERING FOR PRODUCTION (MLOPS)

Credential ID: 9AGVYPBRNTU3

GENERATIVE ADVERSARIAL NETWORKS (GANS)

Credential ID: LG6Z86YY3EWU

DEEPLEARNING.AI TENSORFLOW DEVELOPER

Credential ID: F5ZGQ824QGUQ

DEEP LEARNING

Credential ID: YB5FJEBQPBWC

PYTHON 3 PROGRAMMING

Credential ID: PYDF6Z923PQ8

APPLIED DATA SCIENCE WITH PYTHON

Credential ID: H8HDLSL7AMNU